[laughing] Yes!
Looks like a geyser
just gone off!
Fresh salvage!
Wait till you see
all this, Cole!
So there's junk everywhere
in the Land of Lost Things,
but you're excited
about this particular junk?
We're in Sector Four!
Lots of quality gear
spews out in Sector Four.
You've got a lot
to learn, newbie.
[laughing]
[gasping] A new book!
"Boobytraps
and How to Survive Them."
Huh, people sure seem to lose
a lot of copies of these.
[Spitz] Cool!
Look what I found!
[roaring]
[screaming]
[cawing]
[yelping] No! No, no, no, no!
It's back, it's back!
[gasping and sobbing]
Fritz!
I'm sorry, I forgot!
Fritz's village
was attacked by a monster.
It's how he ended up here.
Fritz, it's okay.
Spitz didn't mean it.
You're safe.
[sighing] I am?
Sure.
You'll always be safe with me.
All of you.
[Kai's voice] ...Cole?
Cole...?
Cole! Are you still with us?
[Cole] The trail's leading
straight to Imperium.
Come on!
[people panicking]
[screaming]
[gasping]
Where's Nokt?
He's the one behind this,
and we gotta get the Finders
back to normal.
I don't see him anywhere!
[Percival] Everyone!
Get to cover!
There's too many of them! Run!
[snarling]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
No!
Roby, talk to me!
[roaring affectionately]
Womp womp...
Just like all the people
in the Land of Lee.
Yeah, but with this guy,
being hollow
really improves
his personality, am I right?
Ah!
Don't insult my boyfriend!
Hold up,
you actually, unironically
like that guy?
For real?
With all his "stangs"
and his "zoots"
and his "womp, womp."
He's like if the sound
of an airhorn
became a person.
That beautiful genius
is worth more than ten of you,
you goodness-shattered freak
with bad breath!
[sniffing]
Stop this!
Roby being hollow
also means we can't learn
how to stop ThunderFang
and his Spectral Invasions.
[Arin] Maybe they could help?
The Security Bots! Of course!
No souls to drain.
Excuse us,
we need information
on the ancient battle between--
The lore
of the City of Temples
cannot be granted to the public
without an appropriate order.
Okay.
I order you to tell us about--
[bot] Order rejected.
Unauthorized user.
Please apply
to Gamesmaster Roby
for authorization.
Womp, womp...
That's not happening
any time soon.
So this is just a dead end?
There's still one person
who can tell us
what we need to know,
if he hasn't been
hollowed out too.
Who?
You won't like it.
Come on.
We're going to the dungeons.
[unearthly shrieking]
The Red Ninja?
Thank the Sources!
H'ah!
I'm gonna mess you goons up.
Hey'ah!
And you brought... some guy.
H'yah! Ha!
A little to the left!
No, uh, your left.
Okay, more... more...
Almost.
[unearthly shrieking]
H'yah!
[Frak] I definitely
hit some too.
[Cole] I'm sure.
Prismatic Steel.
Like the lenses in my goggles.
[unearthly shrieking]
Can we use those?
I'm kinda in the middle
of using this, Percival.
No, we need--
[instrument blowing
spectral note]
[blowing spectral note]
The souls of the people
they're draining
are going in that thing!
That must be the key
to saving the Finders!
[blowing spectral note]
[groaning] Ugh...
This walking tour
gets negative five stars.
Do not recommend.
Could you just tell us
why we're here, Wyldfyre?
To talk to the traitor.
Roby's Uncle Bleckt?
The old jerk was
Mr. Ledger-meister or whatever.
If anyone knows what we need
to know, it's him.
Oh, wait, so the plan
is trust the guy
who made a deal with Ras
to backstab his own nephew?
[laughing derisively]
This'll go great.
Halt.
The prisoner is not allowed
unauthorized visitors.
This is an emergency.
The fate of the Merged Lands
hangs in the balance.
Access denied
by order of the Gamesmaster.
Guess they only listen to Roby.
You heard the lady.
Back away!
Negative.
Unauthorized user.
Fine.
Then eat lightning!
Negative. We are not hungry.
These bots were designed
as security
for the Tournament
of the Sources.
Elemental powers
aren't gonna work on them.
Let's see if feet work.
No, wait!
Alert!
We are under attack!
Defend and apprehend!
H'yah!
[grunting with effort]
Ha! H'yup!
Hey!
Back off!
Hey, bots...
Do jumping jacks.
Now dance a jig.
[♪♪♪]
What's the deal here?
Gamesmaster Roby instructed us
that should he ever
become incapacitated
that User Wyldfyre
is to be afforded
all-access authority.
I'm his backup contact?
Oh, Roby, you cutie!
Hmm, so I basically
command my own city now?
Interesting.
Interesting...
Romantic relationships
make no sense to me.
Especially
this romantic relationship.
Wyldfyre, we're still
on a mission.
Get the bots
to take us to Bleckt.
Of course.
These are seedless, right?
Roby would want me
to have seedless.
I knew it'd go to her head,
just not this fast.
To what do I owe this...
"honor," hmm?
Come to gloat
about my fall from grace?
We're here about the invasion.
Invasion?
You don't know?
The isolation of this cell
has put a knowledge of history
even more firmly at my command,
but current events
somewhat elude me.
Faster.
There's too much hot air
in here.
The Merged Lands
are being attacked.
Spectral beings
are hollowing people out.
They got Roby
and countless others so far.
I've read of such
Spectral Invasions,
but never imagined
it could actually happen.
There's this dragon,
ThunderFang.
We stopped him once,
and he died,
but that didn't slow him down
as much as you'd expect.
There are some things
that only grow stronger
in the rot of death.
I'm not surprised
that blasphemous old lizard
is one of them.
He tried to become
a Source Dragon.
Such unthinkable heresy
is beyond evil.
He was once defeated here
in the City of Temples, right?
We need you to teach us
how it was done.
I can not only tell you,
I can show you,
but not from this cell.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what are you trying to pull?
Professor Pompous here
knows all the secret passages
in this place.
As soon as our backs
are turned,
he's gonna bolt
and turn on the booby traps
or something.
Bleckt might be a villain,
but he loves the Source Dragons.
He understands the stakes here
better than anyone.
Stakes, schmakes!
We can't free this clown
after he tried
to get rid of Roby.
Her logic is terrible,
but her conclusion is right.
You can't let him out.
He looks frail,
but his knowledge
makes him dangerous!
More dangerous
than what's out there already?
I agree with Sora.
I vote we take the risk.
It's not really
a voting situation.
There's only one person here
with the authority
to free a prisoner.
Your call, Wyldfyre.
What's it going to be?
[Cole] I'm taking him down!
[Kai] You can't just run off.
Nokt's one of the most dangerous
of the Forbidden Five.
Remember what he did to me?
I need to get
the Finders' souls
out of that...
thing he's playing!
[Frak] How?
Even our Prismatic Blades
barely hurt these creatures.
That's what
I was trying to say!
When we learned what
was happening in other lands,
these weird things attacking,
the Advanced Science Lab
designed new Prismatic Blades
to eliminate them permanently.
Then why aren't we
using them?
They're designed, not built.
We need Prismatic Steel
forged with soul energy,
and we only had barely enough
regular Prismatic Ore
for my lenses here.
But your blades!
We can upgrade them
and stop these things!
Then what are we waiting for?
We don't have time
to run off to some lab.
Nokt is right there!
Cole, stop.
The hot-headed vibe
is usually my thing.
Think this through.
You don't understand.
I should've protected
the Finders.
You're letting your emotions
take over, and--
You're not my teacher, Kai!
Protect Percival
and get your blades upgraded.
Let's get this done.
Fast.
[tires squealing]
I've decided...
that I need a shoulder massage
to help me decide.
Wyldfyre...
Okay, fine!
As acting President,
Prime Minister,
Boss of the City of Temples,
I've come to a decision.
Release Bleckt.
Don't even think about running.
I never run.
I walk in a stately manner.
Follow me.
The secrets you need
are kept hidden
in the Vault of Focus.
To enter the vault,
I must speak the pass-phrase.
Turn around
and cover your ears.
Yeah, right. We turn, you run.
We're not
taking our eyes off you.
Make with the pass-phrase,
Bleckty.
[grumbling]
I hereby acknowledge
that Roby is so dope
that I can't even.
Zoot-zoot.
[laughing]
[mechanism clanking]
Hmm, probably a trap.
Next one down that pole
is a goner.
Your funeral, Greenie.
Oh, well,
it was nice knowing him.
I mean, not really.
[chuckling]
So neurotic.
[Lloyd calling] Ninja!
It's okay, I'm safe!
But, well...
it's a lot.
Come see.
Is this all built with...
[Bleckt] Prismatic Steel.
The City of Temples
sits on a deposit of raw ore.
It was mixed with soul energy
to create the chains
for ThunderFang,
the Shatter Dragon of Chaos.
Chaos is
an almost unstoppable force,
but it has a natural enemy...
Focus.
[tapping pillar]
That's
the Source Dragon of Focus?
No.
The Arc Dragon of Focus,
a mortal avatar
of the Focus Source Dragon.
Only the Council of Sources
can vote to release it.
We can't count on the vote
going our way this time.
I have reason to believe
the Source Dragons
are deadlocked
about helping mortals.
If that's true,
then chaos will reign.
But I've heard
there's a way for mortals
to wake the Arc Dragon of Focus.
There might be,
but the consequences
could be disastrous.
We never back down
from disastrous consequences.
Even when we really should.
Summoning
the Source Dragons' champion
without their permission
could mark you as an enemy
of the Sources.
But if we don't,
ThunderFang could destroy
the Source Dragons
and the Merged Lands.
If you're going to risk
such an action,
you will need this...
...the Unbidden Storm.
[spectral note reverberating]
[heroic music playing]
[screaming]
Hurry, Cole's out there alone!
[power surging]
It has never been done,
but when the Arc Dragon of Focus
is inactive,
it rests
the two halves of itself
in two caves.
Each must be awakened separately
by a spell-song,
this song--
[bells chiming]
--exactly note by note.
[bell song chiming]
Then, once they're awake,
the Unbidden Storm
must be brought to the place
where the Arc Dragon
is to be summoned...
in this case,
as close to ThunderFang's
source of power as possible...
but such actions
have never been attempted
by mortals before.
It's the only shot we have.
Where are the two halves
of the dragon?
One half is in
Mysterium's Cave of Bells,
but the other half,
I'm sorry to tell you,
was in Djinjago,
which has been destroyed.
Not anymore. It's back.
ThunderFang and Djinjago
are back?
No one tells me anything!
But Djinjago is only
a sliver of its former self.
So maybe the cave
where this thing sleeps
isn't even there yet?
Even if you do wake up
both halves, then what?
March right into
the Spectral Lands
to summon it?
You'd be eviscerated
at the border!
[sighing]
Meany-breath has a point.
The last time we entered
the Spectral Lands,
you barely escaped alive.
I mean, I was fine,
but you all? [scoffing]
I might have an idea
about that.
Anyone want to visit
the junkyard?
Time for a field test!
H'yah!
This is for the Finders!
[unearthly shrieking]
There they are!
[gasping and struggling]
Cole!
[groaning]
[blowing spectral note]
[revving engine]
H'yah!
[grunting with impact]
[panting]
Is he...?
Alive,
but...
he's hollow.
[sighing] Cole,
why didn't you listen?
[unearthly shrieking overhead]
[shrieking]
H'ah!
It works!
[shrieking]
[blowing spectral note]
Nokt!
Your music's terrible!
Citizens of Imperium!
Thanks to the Ninja,
once again, our city is free!
[cheering]
[hollowed people moaning]
You did it!
But look at the cost.
Whatever this Sora kid's up to
better be worth it.
[Lloyd] What are you
looking at, Bleckt?
If ThunderFang
has gathered enough souls
to attempt to become
a Source Dragon,
the immense power
will be visible
from all the Merged Lands.
So it's good
we don't see anything.
[Bleckt] Yet.
What do you think?
Specially designed
for the Spectral Lands.
I went to the junkyard
to build these mechs,
and Wyldfyre ordered bots
to bring me some Prismatic Ore
to cover them with.
So they're impervious
to spectral attack?
That's not entirely stupid.
More like brilliant!
This is the chance we need
to get all the way
to ThunderFang at the Well!
[Lloyd] Great work, Sora.
Okay, team, we've got a plan,
sort of,
but we have to move fast.
Let's go.
The bots will take you
back to your cell,
and if you lied
about any of this,
I'll come back
and authorize your life
to be miserable forever.
I am not betting
on your chances of success.
Always such a downer, Bleckt.
May the Source Dragons
forgive us.
[blowing spectral note]
[ThunderFang] So few souls?
Is not Imperium
a vastly populated land?
[blowing spectral note]
Now, that's more like it.
Finally!
I have collected
all the power I will need!
[distant thunder rumbling]
[Lloyd] Bleckt warned us
this was coming.
We've gotta go now!
Okay, last time. Arin?
You and I will take
this Unbidden Storm thing
to the Well of the Lost,
and can summon the Arc Dragon
once its two halves are awake.
Good. Sora and Wyldfyre?
We'll get Zanth
to take us to Djinjago.
If this Cave of Tones exists,
which I really hope it does,
we ring the Spell Song.
Okay. Nya and Jay?
[Nya] We'll go to Mysterium,
ring the spell song,
and wake the dragon's
other half.
Yeah, except I'm not doing
any of that.
I've already done
more than I bargained for
on this little trip.
You can't bail
on saving the world.
That's not what Ninja do.
I'm not a ninja!
Why can't you all get that
through your heads?
You hired me for one job!
I did it,
and you still haven't paid me
or helped me capture Ras!
I thought Ninja
kept their word.
We've been a little busy.
Yeah. Busy
nearly getting me killed,
and I'm done.
I really believed,
after all we'd been through,
that you'd care about
something other than yourself.
I thought I saw glimpses
of your old self,
moments
where you knew the truth,
that you were a hero,
but I was wrong.
Try not to die
before you pay me.
Nya, if you--
Lloyd,
we've got a world to save.
[Wyldfyre gasping]
Good luck, everybody!
We're gonna need it.
[gates closing]
[Ras growling]
[♪♪♪]